Congratulations, everyone.
In 1988, the first time I lived it,
Kayo, Hiromi, and Aya Nakanishi disappeared,
and their bodies were found later.
I was too helpless to save anyone.
I tried hard to forget, and I did,
but in the end, I had a big gaping hole in my heart.
These past six years, we've experienced success and failure,
happiness and sadness.
Good or bad, the experiences we share fill a void we all have inside of us.
Everyone, even me.
So keep filling it, and you'll enrich your life and others, too.
That's what life's about. Never forget that.
カメラー イラスト
君を待った、僕は待った。
途切れない明日も過ぎたって。
立ち止まって、振り返って。
止めどない今日を嘆きあった。
記憶だって永遠にだって残らないもんと思い知って僕はずっとかきむしって心をすびっこで泣いた そしてどうかなくさないでよって後悔した過ぎる日々を後悔したんだよってそう言い逃したあの日
君を待った 僕は待った 途切れない明日も過ぎてって 僕は今日もかきむしって忘れない傷をつけてるんだよ
Oh oh oh oh oh oh I'll give me the night of the sun
Whoa! Yeah!
Yeah!
Hey there!
Who are you?
I'm Satoru Fujinuma.
I'm Kenya Kobayashi.
I'm Hiromi Sugita.
Have we met before?
Uh, Ira Ayanaka Nishi, I heard you're good at piano.
Yeah, I guess.
So, did we meet in piano class?
Well, actually no.
So, anyway, whatcha reading?
Oh, this? Shakespeare?
King Lear? I've only read Romeo and Juliet.
Reading this stuff and playing piano are my parents' idea.
I can't hear what they're talking about.
Maybe we should try and get a little closer.
Wait! Now I remember where I've seen you before!
You're the kids who are always sneaking into that old building, aren't you?
Darn it. So much for having a secret hideout.
Hideout? That's so childish.
Y-you shouldn't call it childish.
Yeah, well, the only ones who sneak around building forts and secret hideouts are little boys.
I bet you like playing superhero, too.
Don't make fun of superheroes!
Easy, Satoru!
Nice meeting you, but I have to go now.
Bye, kids.
Hold up!
Kazu?
What do you want?
A hideout?
Is totally macho!
You should come and see it sometime!
You'll get what I mean!
You're a bunch of weirdos!
She's childish.
You were so rad yesterday!
It's my gloves.
Right where I left him 18 years ago.
Leveling up's a pain in the nuts!
That's what makes games fun!
Hey, Satoru.
Aya's gonna be at the park soon, so maybe we should start heading over.
Is cool.
I can see the bench from here.
Okay.
Yesterday was a wash.
I gotta figure out how to get close to her.
Alright, I'm here to see this macho hideout of yours.
Um, thanks for coming, Aya!
Can you stay a while?
Mm-hmm.
See you! Bye-bye!
You have to see Aya again?
Yep.
We'll cruise by the hideout later.
Well, guys, see you then!
Later days, Teach!
Goodbyes more proper.
I can't picture Aya and Kazu liking each other.
Yeah, me neither.
But the good thing is, she's always got someone with her now.
Mm-hmm.
Um, you guys, I...
I just wanted to say thank you.
Why?
I think it's awesome how you're going around and making sure none of us are alone.
Both of my parents work.
And nothing felt worse than me getting home and the house being empty.
It's pretty awesome how you kept Kaio and Aya and me from being alone all the time.
So thank you!
Hey!
Guys!
We going to the hideout or what?
I'm getting tired of waiting.
What's up?
Where's Kazu?
He went to go meet Aya.
How come?
You're joking, right?
It's not like she doesn't know where our hideout is.
Maybe you should talk to him.
Well, whatever.
Let's get going already.
Okay.
Goodbye, Mr. Yashiro.
Slopehooks!
What's the rush?
Wait up, guys!
Aya Nakanishi, Hiromi Sugita, and Kaio Hinazuki.
They're all still alive, so I guess that means the killer gave up on them.
But now that the clues from the bus are gone, how am I going to find him?
There! Now he really looks like a girl!
Whoa!
Now what?
Are you done?
You know, playing detective?
Not yet.
I'm still on the case.
In 2006, my mom told Sawada she thought she knew who the killer was.
It's possible it's someone she knows now.
In 1988.
Maybe like Mr. Yashiro and his candy, the killer needs a substitute too.
Someone to take the place of the kids that got away.
Move it.
Well, me and Ken are heading out now to go watch the hockey game.
Is Hamada playing?
You know it.
Wish I could go.
When you see him, tell him I said good luck.
Sure.
See you later.
Here I am.
You notice how Misato's been keeping to herself lately?
No.
Really?
Yeah.
People have been avoiding her ever since that lunch money thing happened.
Oh man.
I guess I could try talking to her on Monday.
Cool.
Thanks for breakfast!
Oh yeah.
I might be a little late today.
Not too late, I hope.
When you know what time, how about you call and let me know.
Okay?
Mm-hmm.
I will.
See you later, Mom!
Have a good day today, Satoru!
Mr. Yashiro's gonna take us.
Really?
You know who will have to walk over there.
Too bad for her.
What can I say to her?
Crap.
Mr.
You know who will have to walk over there.
Too bad for her.
What can I say to her?
Crap.
Mr.
Satoru, I heard you're gonna try helping Misato next.
Mm-hmm.
But she just left.
I bet she's going to walk up a gym.
Really?
Yeah.
Hamura's playing so Mr. Yashiro invited her to go cheer him on.
You know what?
She went to last week's game alone too.
Thanks.
Want us to go with you?
Nah.
She went to last week's game alone, too.
Thanks.
Want us to go with you?
Nah, I think I better do this myself.
It's no biggie.
Okay.
But I want a full report tomorrow.
Got it, Detective Satoru?
Sure.
We'll be at the hideout if you need backup.
See you later!
Later, dude!
See you tomorrow!
You got it!
See ya!
Bye, you guys!
Tain Vi is a big deal with him.
I know, right?
He acts like he'll never see us again.
Whoa!
It's even colder in here than outside.
Hamada!
Show him who's boss out there!
I can't concentrate with you!
Ugly's yelling!
We can yell if we want.
Watch the attitude, Koichi!
Otherwise, no dinner for you!
What?
But they're bugging me!
There she is.
And she's alone.
Alright, guys.
Warm up and get your game face on.
Yes, sir!
Now the killer's lost two more potential victims.
It makes sense he'd go for her next.
She's a perfect target.
Oh, Daddy!
She's going to the bathroom.
Game starts in five!
Okay, Coach!
Why is she taking so long?
I needed a candy break.
What's wrong?
The game's about to start.
Are you standing guard for someone?
Huh?
Oh, uh, no!
I just wanted to talk to Misato.
Misato?
Hmm.
What?
Did she go outside?
Uh-huh.
Where'd she take off to?
What?
That's Yuki's dad's truck!
Mr. Yoshiro,
I need to follow someone.
Will you drive?
Huh?
That doesn't even sound legal.
It's nothing bad.
We're just plain detective.
We pretend there's a kidnapper at large.
Then we try to find girls who seem like they're lonely
and make friends with them.
If anything,
we could end up stopping a real kidnapping.
My God.
It might be just a game,
but it's a good idea.
I'm glad you think so.
Satoru,
better buckle up.
Oh, yeah.
I have to get that fixed.
There.
So,
you've noticed Misato's been keeping to herself lately.
Actually,
Hiromi told me a little while ago.
Well,
if you ask me,
it's great you're being so proactive about it.
I don't know about that.
I couldn't get up the nerve
to talk to her before,
and,
well,
I started thinking
she might make good bait.
Really?
Bait?
So you're out to catch someone.
Now I know why you were working so hard
to be friendly and outgoing.
You're a man on a mission.
Mm-hmm.
Everybody has something
that's missing from their lives,
even me.
If I can fill that void...
Crap.
We just fed him his own line.
You and I have a lot in common.
That happens to be my philosophy in life.
When I teach a sixth grade class,
I like to bring it up in my graduation speech.
It sort of ties into what you said
about using Misato as bait.
I can tell you regret it,
but in my opinion,
you shouldn't.
There's no difference between a good deed
and a bad one.
They both have a similar goal,
to satisfy a need within a person.
Wow, that's...
extreme.
For example,
lately,
I've tried all kinds of things
to get closer to someone.
Sometimes I'm direct.
Other times,
I play coy.
At times,
I've even been deceitful.
And boy,
it's been fun.
With who?
A girlfriend?
Ha ha!
I can see how you'd make that connection.
Hmm.
Either way,
it's about filling
some kind of emptiness.
Um...
want a lollipop?
Thank you for asking,
but I'm afraid
you won't find any there.
You see,
this
isn't
my car.
Where's your car, then?
In the shop?
Whatever your happiest moment is today,
another will eventually come along
to replace it.
And thanks to you,
mine just got replaced.
Nothing compares to the feeling
a person gets
when they can finally satisfy their need.
You spend all this time
searching,
and when you get it,
it's like heaven.
You know,
it's true what they say.
The more effort something takes,
the sweeter the reward is.
Where the hell's he going with this?
Laxatives?
Satoru,
you lied to me
a few minutes ago.
You said you're just
pretending there's a kidnapper,
but the truth is,
you know there's one,
and you're trying to catch him.
I've resisted the idea
for a while now
because I couldn't believe
it was possible.
Well,
more like I didn't want to believe.
The possibility
that someone
was anticipating
my every move.
If you're still worried
about Misato,
don't be.
The only person
in that truck
is Jun Shiratori's father.
I realized
something was up with you
the day I saw you
following Aya Nakanishi,
and I was planning
to kidnap her
the day I gave you
and your mom a ride.
Looking back,
it's kind of funny.
I mean,
there you were
trying to snatch my prey
and I was the one
telling you how to do it.
That was the second time
you ruined my plans,
and I started to suspect
it was more than
a coincidence.
I knew Misato's friends
were shunning her,
so I asked her
to the hockey game.
Then I told Hiromi
about it.
If you showed up
my suspicions
were correct
that you,
you were my enemy.
No way.
When the time
was right,
I gave Misato a drink
laced with that
laxative you found,
and I bought dinner
to place Shiratori
at the scene.
No.
No!
Yes, sir,
all the pieces
fit together,
as planned.
And in the end,
I'm not who
you thought I was.
Oh, and about the car,
I borrowed this one earlier.
I was looking for something
specific for today.
Generic model,
generic paint job,
a car that's so ubiquitous
no one would even miss it.
You know,
this is the first time
I've put that theory
into practice.
How could I be so stupid?
It was so obvious.
Thanks to you,
Kaio's alive.
I just couldn't accept
the possibility.
Yashiro was on one
of Sawada's lists
of suspects,
but my mom's name
was right there,
with his,
so I figured the list
was bullshit
and blew it off.
I trusted him so much,
I couldn't even think
of him as a suspect,
let alone the killer.
But,
he is.
And now he's got me
right where he wants me.
It started snowing.
Don't.
It stuck for good.
The game's over.
For you,
and me.
You know,
I still can't believe it.
You anticipated
all my plans
and destroyed them
one by one.
I'm stunned
how easily you caught me,
a little boy like you.
It's almost like
you can see the future
or something.
I want to make sure
you understand
why you have to die.
Yes,
you ruined my plans,
but this
has nothing to do
with revenge.
Believe me,
I do respect you.
but if I can't
satisfy my needs
the usual way,
I have to find
an alternative.
You don't have to do this.
You said the game
is over.
The children
of this town
are safe
thanks to you,
Satoru.
So congratulations,
you got what you wanted.
And as for what
I wanted,
I still get to kill
someone for my sake
and on my terms.
Yashiro,
I'm not gonna die
until I see you
hang for what you've done.
Yes,
well,
keep telling yourself that.
Yashiro,
you son of a bitch!
I'll get you for this!
I wish I could stay,
but I have so much
packing to do.
I know your future!
Shit!
It's cold!
Come on!
going
numb
shit!
Mom?
What's up,
kiddo?
I looked up.
Our eyes met.
My friends.
Hi,
Satoru!
Thank you.
Satoru?
Kaio?
Irie?
作詞・作曲・編曲 初音ミク
初音ミク
by
the
you
yeah
You